Guide to the Women in the Urban Crisis Records, 1969-1984 AIS.1985.03
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Women in the Urban Crisis Records
1960-1984
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Women in the Urban Crisis (Pittsburgh, Pa.)
AIS.1985.03
22.25 Linear Feet (18 boxes)
The Women in the Urban Crisis (WIUC) was a non-profit organization that formed as a result of an urban crisis conference held at Chatham College in March of 1969, which attracted women leaders throughout the community. The records contain correspondence, projects, programs, and proposals. In addition, there are organizational files of the WIUC and information pertaining to their annual conferences.
History
Women in the Urban Crisis (WIUC) was a non-profit organization that formed as a result of an urban crisis conference held at Chatham College in March of 1969, which attracted women leaders throughout the community. The conference in Pittsburgh was one of the many that B'nai B'rith Women organized in various cities across the nation following the 1968 assassination of Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr.
The urban crisis refers to various problems which residents of cities face. In Pittsburgh, Women in the Urban Crisis looked at troubles associated with education, employment, health, housing, and welfare. To alleviate these crises the organization set up programs and also worked on joint projects with other organizations in the city.
The organization was headed by a president and elected officers. Five committees, designated for each of the issues listed above, were the most active part of the WIUC and coordinated their efforts with associated orgaizations. Other committees were created as needed for special projects. Additional support came from a board, approximately 50 constituent organizations, and individual members who contributed to the success of Women in the Urban Crisis.
The WIUC served as an umbrella organization which united Pittsburgh's various civil rights and women's organizations to more effectively address the problems of inner-city Pittsburgh. Concerned with the relative ineffectiveness of many individual organizations, often divided by class, race, or religion, the WIUC brought them together to work towards their common goals. The WIUC facilitated the cooperation of their constituent groups on various projects and maintained communication between them. Their annual conferences kept their constituents and community members updated with their progress and goals. The organization focused on an educational approach, raising awareness of the issues in Pittsburgh communities and working to improve the quality of life.
After 15 years of service, Women in the Urban Crisis dissolved in 1984.
Scope and Content Notes
The collection of Women in the Urban Crisis is comprised of eight series contained in fifteen boxes. Additional scope and content notes can be found at the series level. The records include correspondence, projects, programs, and proposals. In addition, there are organizational files of WIUC and information pertaining to their annual conferences. Enhancing the collections are photographs, slides, and newspaper clippings documenting the work of the organization. The bulk of the records range from 1972-1982. The files are arranged alphabetically by subject or name as they were used by the office of origin.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Arlene Stromberg, Women in the Urban Crisis, March 21, 1985.
Previous Citation
Women in the Urban Crisis Records, 1969-1984, AIS.1985.03, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Associations; Social action; Women; Pittsburgh (Pa.) -- Economic conditions; Pittsburgh (Pa.) -- Social conditions; Human rights workers -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Human services -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Child care services -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Women volunteers in social service -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Women in community development -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Action Line (Pittsburgh, Pa.); Call for Action (Pittsburgh, Pa.); Arnold, Charlotte; B'nai B'rith Women; Charles, Marian; Harris, Vivian; Johnson, Katie; KDKA-TV (Television station: Pittsburgh, Pa.); Pickett, Betty; Pittsburgh School District (Pa.). Breakfast Program; Rayvid, Lynn; Reizenstein, Florence; Shapira, Frieda; Ware, Grace; Women in the Urban Crisis (Pittsburgh, Pa.); WPXI (Television station: Pittsburgh, Pa.)
- Correspondence, 1969-1984; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  The correspondence of the organization is an extensive part of the collection filed in six boxes. There is correspondence with individuals, local businesses, legislators, and various local and national organizations. The large amount of correspondence demonstrates the action-oriented approach that WIUC used to accomplish their goals.
  - Correspondence A-C, 1969-1984; 1.
    - A-Letters to Individuals, 1969-1981 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Able-1 Answering Service, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Action Coalition of Elders, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Action for Children's Television, 1970-1973 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Action Housing, 1978-1984 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Action-Washington, D.C., undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Ad Hoc Committee on School Board Selection, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Ad Hoc Committee to Save the Children, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Ad Hoc Lawyers Committee, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Adult Services, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Aeronauts International, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - African Heritage Classroom, 1975-1978 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Afro-Asian Festival, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Afro-Technical Educational Consultants (AF-TEC), undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Alcoa Foundation, 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Allegheny Airlines, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Allegheny Center, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Allegheny Children's Center, undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Allegheny Conference on Community Development, 1970-1979 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Allegheny Conference on Environmental Systems Services, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Allegheny County, Bar Association, 1975-1981 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Allegheny County, Board of Assistance, 1971-1976 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Allegheny County, Board of Consumer Affairs, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Allegheny County, Children Youth Service, 1975-1980 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Allegheny County, Child Welfare Services, 1972-1977 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Allegheny County, Commissioners, 1968-1979 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Allegheny County, Community Development, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Allegheny County, Council- Camp Fire Girls, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Allegheny County, Council on Civil Rights, 1972-1982 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Allegheny County, Court on Civil Pleas, 1970-1974 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Allegheny County, Environmental, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Allegheny County, Environmental Coalition, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Allegheny County, Foster Home Department, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Allegheny County, Government Study Commission, 1973-1977 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Allegheny County, Health Department, 1970-1981 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Allegheny County, Human Services Commission, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Allegheny County, Labor Council, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Allegheny County, Long Term Care for Elderly, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Allegheny County, Medical Assistants Society, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Allegheny County, Medical Society, 1972-1980 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Allegheny County, Mental Health Retardation Plan, 1972-1978 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Allegheny County, Parks and Recreation, 1975-1978 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Allegheny County, Prison, undated (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Allegheny County, Sanitary Authority (ALCOSAN), 1974 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Allegheny County, Schools, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Allegheny County, Sheriff's Office, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - Allegheny County, Taxpayers League, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    - Allegheny East Mental Health Mental Retardation Center, Inc., 1970 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Allegheny Foundation, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Allegheny Housing Rehabilitation Corporation (AHRCO), 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Allegheny Institute for Environmental Studies and Education, undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
    - Allegheny Intermediate Unit, 1977-1984 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    - Allegheny Regional Narcotics Task Force, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    - Allegheny Regional Planning Council, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    - Allegheny Union Baptist Association, Women's Auxiliary, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    - Alliance for Advancement of Health Education, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    - Alliance for Consumer Protection, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    - Alliance for Volunteerism, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Alma Illery Medical Center, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Alpha Wesleyan Service Guild of the First United Methodist Church, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Alternative Education Resource Development, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - American Association of Medical Assistants, Inc., 1972 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - American Association of University Women (AAUW), Fox Chapel Branch, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - American Association of University Women (AAUW), Monroeville Branch, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - American Association of University Women (AAUW), Mt. Lebanon Branch, 1969-1977 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - American Association of University Women (AAUW), Pittsburgh Branch, 1971-1984 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - American Association of University Women (AAUW), Pennsylvania Division, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - American Baptist Women, 1969-1981 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - American Cancer Society, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU), 1972-1984 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    - American Freedom from Hunger Foundation, Inc., 1970 (Box 1, Folder 71)
    - American Friends Service Committee, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - American Jewish Committee, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - American Jewish Congress, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - American Planning Association, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - American Red Cross, 1970-1982 (Box 1, Folder 76)
    - American School Food Service Association, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 77)
    - Americans for Democratic Action- Pittsburgh, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 78)
    - Animal Rescue League, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 79)
    - Anti-Defamation League of B'nai B'rith, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 80)
    - Anti-Inflation Drive, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 81)
    - Arsenal Family Children's Center, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 82)
    - Assembly on University Goals Governance, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 83)
    - Association for Retarded Children, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 84)
    - Association of Community Organizations for Change Now (ACORN), 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 85)
    - Association of Western Pennsylvania Women's Deans, Counselors and Personal Workers, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 86)
    - Atlantic and Pacific Tea Company, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 87)
    - Attorney General, U.S., 1979 (Box 1, Folder 88)
    - Attorney General's Office, Pennsylvania, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 89)
    - B- Letters to Individuals, 1969-1973 (Box 1, Folder 90)
    - Babcock Lumber Company, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 91)
    - Baha'i Assembly of Pittsburgh, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 92)
    - Bakerstown Presbyterian Church, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 93)
    - Baldwin Community Action Committee, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 94)
    - Baltimore, City Police, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 95)
    - Beatrice Foods Company, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 96)
    - Bell Atlantic Telephone Company, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 97)
    - Bellefield Presbyterian Church, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 98)
    - Belmar School PTA, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 99)
    - Bennett Paper Company, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 100)
    - Bethesda United Presbyterian Church United Community Center, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 101)
    - Better Business Bureau (BBB), 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 102)
    - Beulah United Presbyterian Church, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 103)
    - Bicentennial Convocation on Religious Liberty, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 104)
    - BICEP, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 105)
    - Bidwell Recreation Center Bidwell Church, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 106)
    - Binstock, Dorothy, 1972-1981 (Box 1, Folder 107)
    - Birmingham United Church of Christ, undated (Box 1, Folder 108)
    - Black Adoption Services of Three Rivers Adoption Council (TRAC), 1982 (Box 1, Folder 109)
    - Black American Historical Research Center, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 110)
    - Black Guardians, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 111)
    - Black League of Afro-American Culture, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 112)
    - Black Solidarity Fair, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 113)
    - Black Women's Political Caucus, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 114)
    - Bluett and Bluett, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 115)
    - B'nai B'rith Women Greater Pittsburgh Council, 1970-1981 (Box 1, Folder 116)
    - Board of Public Education- Pittsburgh, 1970-1984 (Box 1, Folder 117)
    - Boarding Homes, 1969-1979 (Box 1, Folder 118)
    - Borland Printing Company, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 119)
    - Boy Scouts of America, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 120)
    - Bright Beginners, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 121)
    - Brown Baking Company, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 122)
    - Buhl Foundation, 1971-1984 (Box 1, Folder 123)
    - Bureau of National Affairs, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 124)
    - Business Job Development Corporation, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 125)
    - 4-C, Community Coordinated Child Care, 1972-1976 (Box 1, Folder 126)
    - C- Letters to Individuals, 1970-1980 (Box 1, Folder 127)
    - Camp Achievement, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 128)
    - Campbell Soup Company, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 129)
    - Campership Committee of Greater Pittsburgh, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 130)
    - Carlow College, 1970-1984 (Box 1, Folder 131)
    - Carnegie Library of Pittsburgh, 1971-1981 (Box 1, Folder 132)
    - Carnegie Mellon University, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 133)
    - George Washington Carver Lunch, 1976-1981 (Box 1, Folder 134)
    - Cathedral College of Christian Vocation, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 135)
    - Catholic Social Service of Allegheny County, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 136)
    - Catholic Diocese of Pittsburgh, 1970-1978 (Box 1, Folder 137)
    - Catholic Inter Racial Council, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 138)
    - Center for Community Affairs, Indiana University of Pennsylvania, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 139)
    - Center for Pregnant School Area Girls, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 140)
    - Central Medical Foundation, 1975-1982 (Box 1, Folder 141)
    - Ceta (Job Power) Allegheny County, 1977-1981 (Box 1, Folder 142)
    - Chamber of Commerce, 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 143)
    - Chatham College, 1971-1981 (Box 1, Folder 144)
    - Child Abuse Bill, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 145)
    - Children's Lobby of Western Pennsylvania, 1976-1981 (Box 1, Folder 146)
    - Concern for Health Options: Information, Care Education (CHOICE), 1980 (Box 1, Folder 147)
    - Christian Associates of Southwest Pennsylvania, 1970-1977 (Box 1, Folder 148)
    - Christ United Methodist Church, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 149)
    - Church Women United, 1969-1977 (Box 1, Folder 150)
    - Churchill Area Schools, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 151)
    - Cincinnati, City Police, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 152)
    - Citizen Education/ Action Group for Criminal Justice, 1973-1977 (Box 1, Folder 153)
    - Citizen Coalition for Pittsburgh Trial Board Reform, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 154)
    - Citizens Advisory Group, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 155)
    - Citizens Committee, Allegheny County Parks Recreation and Conservation Plan, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 156)
    - Citizenship Information Center, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 157)
    - City Government Study Commission, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 158)
    - City Times, undated (Box 1, Folder 159)
    - Civic Organizations, undated (Box 1, Folder 160)
    - Clean Community Association, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 161)
    - Coalition for Human Needs, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Coalition on National Priorities Military Policy, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - College Club of Pittsburgh, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Columbia Gas Company, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Colville, Bob, 1974-1976 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Combined Parents Legislative Action Committee, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Committee for Integrated Schools, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Common Cause, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Community Action Pittsburgh (CAP), 1971-1981 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Community Action Regional Training (CART), 1972 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Cablevision, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Community Change, Inc., 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Community College of Allegheny County, Allegheny Campus, 1970-1981 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Community of Reconciliation, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Community Relations Committee of the United Jewish Federation, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Community Release Agency, 1971-1974 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Community Services of Pennsylvania, 1970-1978 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Concerned Workers of Westinghouse Electric Corporation, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Condolences, 1970-1985 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Condors, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Conference on Women's Ministries, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Constituent Organizations, 1973-1981 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Consumer Coalition, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Consumer Credit Counseling Service of Western Pennsylvania, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Contact, Pittsburgh, Inc., 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Continental Casualty Company, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Copenhagen, Denmark, '80 Conference, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Coro Foundation, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Corporation Lists, undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Council House, Inc., 1972 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - County Conference Committee, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Create, Inc., undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence D-F, 1969-1984; 2.
    - D- Letters to Individuals, 1969-1980 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Deprived Poor Americans, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Department of Community Affairs, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Displaced Homemakers, 1977-1981 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Letters to Donors, 1970-1984 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Duquesne Light Company, 1973-1984 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Duquesne University, 1970-1975 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - E- Letters to Individuals, 1970-1976 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - East End Education Committee, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - East Liberty Chamber of Commerce, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - East Liberty Garfield Citizens Council, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - East Liberty Presbyterian Church, 1971-1981 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - East Hills Merchants Association (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Ebony Preparatory School, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Educational Medical School, 1975-1978 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Eighth United Presbyterian Church, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Environment: Pittsburgh, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Environmental Planning Information Center of Pittsburgh, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Episcopal Churchwomen, 1969-1974 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Episcopal Diocese of Pittsburgh, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Equal Rights Amendment, 1970-1976 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Equitable Gas Company, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Executive Women's Council, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - F- Letters to Individuals, 1970-1974 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - Falk, Maurice Medical Fund, 1971-1984 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Family Addiction Control Education Program (FACE), 1971 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Family and Childrens Service, 1970-1977 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Family Planning Center of Wilkinsburg, undated (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Family Planning Council of Western Pennsylvania, 1971-1979 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Farm Workers, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - First Baptist Church of Pittsburgh, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - First Unitarian Church, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - First Variable Rate Fund, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Food, Nutrition, and Dairy Council, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Food Stamps, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Ford Foundation, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Forest Hills Women's Club, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Fraternal Order of Police, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Freedom House, 1969-1974 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Frick School Parent Representatives, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Friends of Farm Workers, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Fund for Aid of Neighbors in Need, 1969-1971 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Correspondence G-I, 1969-1984; 3.
    - G- Letters to Individuals, 1969-1981 (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Garfield Area Community Outreach, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - Generations Together, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Georgia State University, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - Gimbels, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - Glen Hazel Area Citizens Union, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - Governor, 1970-1984 (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - Governor's Commission on Mortgage Interest Rates, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Governor's Committee for the Physically Handicapped, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - Governor's Justice Committee- Pennsylvania, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - Greater Pittsburgh Business Development Corporation, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - Greater Pittsburgh Direct Action Coalition, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - Greater Pittsburgh Guild for the Blind, 1971-1981 (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - Group Against Smog and Pollution (GASP), 1969-1984 (Box 2, Folder 88)
    - Group for Recycling in Pennsylvania (GRIP), 1971-1981 (Box 2, Folder 89)
    - Group W (Westinghouse Broadcasting Company, Inc.), 1974-1980 (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - Guardians, 1970-1977 (Box 2, Folder 91)
    - Gulf Oil Corporation, 1970-1974 (Box 2, Folder 92)
    - H-Letters to Individuals, 1970-1981 (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - Hadassah, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 94)
    - Happiness of Womenhood, Inc. (HOW), 1972 (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - Hartford, The John A. Foundation, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 96)
    - Hazelwood, Glenwood, Glen Hazel Council, Inc., 1972 (Box 2, Folder 97)
    - Health Welfare Association of Allegheny County, 1970-1973 (Box 2, Folder 98)
    - Health Welfare Planning Association (HWP), 1974-1984 (Box 2, Folder 99)
    - Health Education Center, HWP, 1978-1982 (Box 2, Folder 100)
    - Health Research Services Foundation of the United Fund, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 101)
    - Health Systems Agency of Southwestern Pennsylvania, 1976-1981 (Box 2, Folder 102)
    - Heinz, Senator John, 1979-1982 (Box 2, Folder 103)
    - Heinz, Howard- Endowment, 1972-1978 (Box 2, Folder 104)
    - Heinz Company Foundation, 1970-1984 (Box 2, Folder 105)
    - Hiland Presbyterian Church, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 106)
    - Hill District Citizens Community Action Development, Inc., 1971-1976 (Box 2, Folder 107)
    - Hill District Federal Credit Union, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 108)
    - Hill House Association, 1972-1981 (Box 2, Folder 109)
    - Hillman Foundation, Inc., 1970-1974 (Box 2, Folder 110)
    - Home for Crippled Children, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 111)
    - Home Rule, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 112)
    - Homestead Hospital, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 113)
    - Homewood- Brushton Clean-up Coalition, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 114)
    - Homewood-Brushton Community Improvement, Inc., 1971-1981 (Box 2, Folder 115)
    - Homework Hotline Advisory Council, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 116)
    - Hope for the Addict, Inc., 1972-1974 (Box 2, Folder 117)
    - Hope Lutheran Church, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 118)
    - Horne Company, Joseph, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 119)
    - Housing Urban Development, 1970-1974 (Box 2, Folder 120)
    - Housing Authority, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 121)
    - Human Relations, Mayor's Commission on, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 122)
    - Human Relations Testimony by WIUC, 1973-1976 (Box 2, Folder 123)
    - Humanities Grant Information, 1976-1980 (Box 2, Folder 124)
    - Hunger Action Coalition, 1979-1983 (Box 2, Folder 125)